<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on kcindric</title>
    <link>https://www.kcindric.me/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on kcindric</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 12:59:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kcindric.me/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Column PostgreSQL Full Text Search</title>
      <link>https://www.kcindric.me/posts/multiple-column-psql-full-text-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 12:59:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kcindric.me/posts/multiple-column-psql-full-text-search/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1 of this tutorial about full text search using PostgreSQL, we talked about using functions such as to_tsquery and websearch_to_tsquery, which builds upon PostgreSQL ability to decompose longer sentences to smaller chunks called lexemes using tsquery.
Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to expand our knowledge and implement multi-column full text search and add indexes for a more performant search. In this next step we want to search film titles AND film descriptions using our dvdrental database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move PostgreSQL data folder to another disk on Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.kcindric.me/posts/psql-move-to-new-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 10:11:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kcindric.me/posts/psql-move-to-new-disk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m running a PostgreSQL 12 instance as a Windows Service on one of my machines and one of the databases is getting too big (~72GB) for my C: drive. I have a great candidate for where to migrate my data - a nearly empty 1TB SSD attached to the machine.
The machine in question is my old Lenovo Thinkpad P51 laptop which I run 24/7 with the lid closed. It has some juciy specs for its time such as 32GB RAM and 4GB GPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostgreSQL Full Text Search</title>
      <link>https://www.kcindric.me/posts/psql-full-text-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 12:59:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kcindric.me/posts/psql-full-text-search/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say we are building an app for searching movies in our private collection. Our app, for simplicity, can only search movies using movie titles. In the following examples we&amp;rsquo;ll show a few different approaches how to do a full text search using PostgreSQL.
In this tutorial we&amp;rsquo;re going to use the sample database called &amp;ldquo;dvdrental&amp;rdquo; which can be found here.
Full Text Search using LIKE and ILIKE operators Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a movie called &amp;ldquo;Darkness War&amp;rdquo; and we want to search it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
